(マダラ)フフフフフ！ ハハハハハ！
At last!
The world of the Infinite Tsukuyomi
is now here!
ついに成ったぞ
無限月読の世界が。
Naruto! You can't right now!
(サスケ)ナルト！ 今はダメだ！
Don't go outside!
Without my Susano'o's protection,
今は 外へ出るな。
you'd be bound up in
his genjutsu as well!
俺の眼で作ったスサノオがなければ
お前も ヤツの幻術にしばられるぞ。
Itachi's Story –
Light and Darkness:
Birth and Death
FIRE
What in the world is going on?!
(ミナト)これは どういうことだ？
WIND
EARTH
LIGHTNING
WATER
(扉間)くっ！ いったい…。
Just what is this?
なんだ これは？
ヤツら 中にいるのか？
Are they inside?
スサノオで光を遮って…。
Blocking the light with the Susano'o?
What's going on outside right now?
(サクラ)外は今 どうなってるの？
(サクラ)サスケ君？
Sasuke?
お前が それを知ってどうする？
What difference will it make,
knowing that?
今のお前にできることは
何もない。
There is nothing
you can do right now.
(カカシ)サスケ そうじゃない。
Sasuke… That's not the point.
(カカシ)それは 俺もナルトも
聞いておきたいことだ。
Naruto and I also want to know.
次の対応を分析するためにも
サクラは…。
In order to analyze our next move,
Sakura is…
カカシ… 今のアンタも サクラと同じだ。
Kakashi…
You're being just like Sakura now.
少し黙ってろ。
(ナルト)テメエ… サスケ！
Just be quiet for a bit.
Hey, Sasuke!
チームワークだっつってんだろうが！
We need to work as a team!
第７班のみんなで
マダラを倒すんだってばよ！
Team 7 needs to work together
to bring Madara down!
(カカシ)確かに
今の俺は何もできない。
You're right.
There's nothing I can do right now…
カカシ先生!?
Kakashi Sensei!
If you can analyze what's outside
with your left eye,
(カカシ)その左眼で
外を分析できるなら 今は サスケ→
Sasuke…
お前が第７班 フォーマンセルの
指揮をとるべきなのも事実。
you should be the one to lead
Team 7's four-man squad.
へぇ～！
コイツが カカシ先生やサクラちゃんより→
Huh?!
I doubt he's better at planning
than either you or Sakura!
作戦ねるのが
うめぇとは思えねえけどな。
俺よりは マシかもしんねえけど…。
Although he may be
better than me…
とにかく マダラの術が発動した。
Anyway…
Madara has activated his jutsu.
強力な幻術だ。
It's a powerful genjutsu.
おそらく外のヤツら
全員その幻術に落ちただろう。
I suspect everyone outside
has fallen under its spell.
助かったのは→
We might be the only ones
俺たちだけかもな。
left unaffected.
無限月読か…。
The Infinite Tsukuyomi, huh?
なら 今頃みんなは…。
So right about now, everyone's…
夢の中だ。
Inside a dream.
Lord Kiba!
キバ様！
(キバ)まず犬の日とか決めて
休日にすっかな。
I think I'll start by establishing
a new holiday called Dog Day!
(赤丸)ワオーン！
火影命令！
It's the Hokage's Decree!
(みんな)お～！
全員 １匹 犬を飼う！
Everyone will own a dog!
Go get a dog!
飼え！ 火影命令！
It's the Hokage's Decree!
(みんな)お～！
(シノ)やっと見つけたぞ 新種を！
I've finally found a new species!
フフフフフ！ よしよし フフフフ！
There, there…
ハハッ ハハハハッ！
Wow!
(チョウジ)うお～！
すんごいごちそう！
What a feast! This looks so tasy!
うまそう！
あなたに食べてほしくて→
I went all out and cooked
all this just for you, dear!
腕を振るったのよ。
Looks like you've found a fan!
(チョウザ)お前もマニアを見つけたな。
いただきま～す！
Thanks for the food!
私 ガツガツ食べる人
男らしくて好き！
I just love gluttons!
I think they're so manly!
あっ！
ごめん。 キミの分まで食べちゃった。
I'm sorry… I ate your share too.
大丈夫。 まだまだあるわよ！
It's okay…
There's so much more!
うお～！ 幸せだな 僕って。
I am so happy!
(ヨシノ)まったく
何度言ったらわかるの？
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
帰りが任務で遅くなるんだったら
連絡してよね！
If you're going to be late
coming back from a mission,
let me know!
(ヨシノ)ご飯をムダに作ったうえに…。
I made dinner for nothing,
(シカマル)結婚なんて 面倒くせぇこと
俺はやめとくか。
- Marriage is such a drag.
- and you kept me waiting.
I think I'll pass.
- Haven't you learned after all these years?
- Yeah.
(テマリ)ああ。
キサマに いのは渡さない。
I won't let you have Ino.
いのは 俺の女だ。 失せろ！
Ino is my woman… Get lost!
(サイ)いえ 僕の女です。
No, she is my woman.
(いの)２人とも ケンカはやめて！
Stop fighting, both of you!
(いのいち)モテるな うちの子。
My daughter's so popular.
(いの)あぁ 困っちゃう。
This is such a pain!
(リー)うお～！ 木ノ葉剛力旋風！
Great Leaf Hurricane!
うわ～っ！
(ネジ)うっ！
青春の勝利です！
Youth prevails!
リーさん！
Oh, Lee!
好きよ！
サクラさん！
I love you!
S-Sakura!
サイ サイ！
- Sai!
おっ サイ。
Oh, Sai.
Hey, Sai.
よう サイ。
(サイ)みんな おはよう。
Good morning, everyone.
おはよ 今日も ステキな笑顔ね。
'Morning.
You have a really nice smile,
as usual.
そうかな？
(いの)ホント サイの笑顔って ステキ！
Do you think so?
You really do have
a beautiful smile, Sai.
It is super cool!
最高です！
いやぁ。
Oh…
Sai! Your smile's the best
in the Hidden Leaf!
サイ！ お前の笑顔は
木ノ葉一だってばよ！
アハハ ハハハ…！
(カンクロウ)ついに完成したじゃん。
I've finally perfected it!
飛ぶじゃん 進むじゃん
俺の究極傀儡！
It flies! It moves!
My ultimate puppet!
砂の願いをのせて お前は
砂の守り神となるんだ！
He embodies all the dreams
of the Sand!
You will be the guardian deity
(カンクロウ)ハッハハハ 行くじゃん！
Let's go!
(カンクロウ)姉上 姉上！
Elder Sister, Elder Sister!
(カンクロウ)姉上 お願いだ。
どうか 知恵を貸してほしい。
Please help me.
I need to pick your brain!
落ち着け どうしたのだ？
Calm down. What is it?
実は…。
(我愛羅)待ってくれ。
You see…
Hold on!
先に 俺の相談にのってくれ！
Let me discuss something
with you first!
お前は もう 風影だ。
自分で判断すればいいだろう。
You're the Kazekage now.
Make your own decisions.
いや どうしても
姉上の意見が聞きたいんだ！
No!
I really want to hear your opinion!
俺もだ！ 頼む 姉上。
Me too! Please, Elder Sister!
It just has to be you!
Elder Sister!
姉上でなければ ならないんだ！
(カンクロウ)姉上！
(我愛羅)姉上！
Elder Sister!
フンッ。
しようがない弟たちだな。
My little brothers are so hopeless.
(テマリ)でね 我愛羅ときたら…。
And then Gaara—!
そうか アカデミーでな。
うん。
Is that so? At the Academy?
Uh-huh!
(夜叉丸)我愛羅様。
お友達が遊びに来てますよ。
Lord Gaara.
Your friend is here to see you.
おっす！
うわぁ。
Hey!
今日は 何して遊ぶ？
外に行こう！
What are we gonna play today?
Let's go outside!
我愛羅。
Gaara…
あまり遅くなるなよ。
Don't stay out too late.
うん。
ヘッ！
Uh-huh.
いつ出られんだよ。
So when can we get outta here?
月の光で幻術にはめるようだ。
It seems the genjutsu
runs on moonlight.
その光は
徐々に 弱まりつつあるが…。
Which will gradually wane.
光のさすうちは ダメだ。
But as long as there's light,
it's useless.
クッソ…。
Damn it!
((イタチ : さよならの前に→
I need to tell you everything
before we part.
お前が確かめたかったことを
教えよう。
もう 嘘をつく必要はない。
There's no need to lie anymore.
(すべての真実を見せよう))
I'll show you the entire truth.
《これは イタチの記憶》
These are Itachi's memories!
Back then, Itachi told me
about the discord
《あのとき イタチは俺に→
木ノ葉の里と うちは一族の
確執を教えてくれたが→
between the Hidden Leaf
and the Uchiha…
それだけではなかった。
but that wasn't all.
記憶だけでなく イタチの知識→
These aren't just memories…
It's Itachi's knowledge,
his thoughts, his suffering…
イタチの思い イタチの苦しみ》
((俺は お前をずっと愛している))
I will love you always…
《うちはイタチという
忍のすべてを…。
It's everything that Itachi Uchiha
the shinobi was…
マダラ お前が うちはを語るな。
Madara…
Don't talk about the Uchiha.
語っていいのは… 兄さんだけだ》
The only one who has that right
is my Big Brother.
((うっ… ぐわ～っ！
(イタチ)これが… 忍界大戦。
So this is…the Great Ninja War.
水… 水！
Water! Water!
す… すまん。
Th-Thank you…
《忍道具？》
Ninja Tools?
父さん なんで この忍は
俺を殺そうとしたの？
Father…
Why did this shinobi
try to kill me?
何もしてないのに。
I didn't do anything…
(フガク)戦争だからだ。
戦争…。
Because this is war.
"War"?
人と人の戦いではない。
It's not a war between people.
It's a war between nations.
国と国の戦いだ。
だから 知らぬ者同士で
互いに意味なく殺し合う。
That's why strangers
kill each other meaninglessly.
そういうものなの？
それが忍の世界だ。
Is that what it is?
That is what the shinobi world is.
Listen, Itachi…
(フガク)いいな イタチ
この光景を忘れるなよ。
Never forget this sight…
(イタチ)うん…。
Uh-huh.
停戦には こぎつけましたが
犠牲が多すぎました。
We managed an armistice,
but the sacrifice was just too great.
責任をとって
三代目は引退するようです。
Lord Third intends to take
full responsibility and retire.
隊長を四代目に推す声もあります。
There are voices in support of
installing you, Captain, as the Fourth Hokage.
どうか…。
その話はよせ。
- Please…
- Enough talk.
はたけカカシは どうしますか？
What should we do
about Kakashi Hatake?
一族の者でもないのに
写輪眼を持っています。
He doesn't belong to our clan,
but he possesses the Sharingan.
(フガク)うちはオビトは
勇敢に戦ったそうだ。
I understand Obito Uchiha
fought bravely.
彼の意志を尊重しよう。
Let's respect his wishes.
写輪眼は
うちはに回収したほうが…。
We should bring the Sharingan
back to the Uchiha…
The war just ended.
戦争が終わったばかりだぞ。
外に いさかいの種をまくな。
はっ。
Do not sow seeds of discord.
Yes, sir.
(フガク)ようやくの平和だ。
束の間であれ 維持に努める。
We finally have peace.
We will persevere to maintain it.
それが うちはの役目だ。
That is the duty of the Uchiha…
ん？
(大蛇丸)死んだ者を
嘆き悲しんでも→
Grieving over the dead
is meaningless.
何の意味もないわ。
死に意味があるとすれば
それが利用できるときだけよ。
If there's any meaning in death,
it's to take advantage of it.
命の意味は何ですか？
What is the meaning of life?
ないわよ。 あるとすれば
命が永遠である場合ね。
There is none.
There's meaning in life if it's eternal.
《命に意味はない…》
There's no meaning…
in life?
くっ！
誰も 死にたくなんかないよね。
No one wants to die, right?
お前たち…。
You guys…
《イタチ : 命って何だろう？》
What is life, anyway?
お大事にね。
(ミコト)ありがとうございます。
Please take care.
Thank you very much!
(イタチ)母さん。
Mom…
(ミコト)何？
What is it?
Are you sick?
(イタチ)どこか悪いの？
Oh, it's nothing like that.
(ミコト)そうじゃないわ。 あのね…。
You see…
あなたに弟か 妹ができるの。
えっ？
You're going to have
a little brother or sister.
そうよ。
あなたは お兄ちゃんになるの。
Yes. You're going to
be a big brother.
(イタチ)母さん。 俺… 弟がいい。
Mom, I want a little brother.
あら 妹だって かわいいわよ。
But a sister will be cute too,
wouldn't it?
弟の気がする。
I have a feeling
it's going to be a little brother.
あら 雪。
Oh!
It's snowing!
夏には生まれるわ。
It will be born in the summer.
男の子よ。 あなたの弟。
It's a boy!
He's your little brother.
《命だ。 新しい命》
A life…
A new life.
名前は決めました？
ああ。
Have you decided on a name?
Yes.
サスケだ。 うちはサスケ。
Sasuke…
Sasuke Uchiha.
(ミコト)あら
いい名前だけど それって…。
Oh… It's a fine name, but that's…
(フガク)ああ 三代目の父上の名だ。
Yes, it's Lord Third's father's name.
I've already asked Lord Third.
三代目には話してある。
そう。
I see.
サスケ。 名に恥じぬよう育てよ。
Sasuke…
We shall raise him to never
dishonor his name.
(フガク)アハハハハ！
そ～ら イタチ。
There, there, Itachi!
Itachi!
イタチ！
ウフフ。 イタチ。
Itachi!
《俺も そうなんだ》
I'm like that too.
《イタチ : 生まれる。 死ぬ。
Birth…death…birth…death…
生まれる。 死ぬ》
(イズミ)ねえねえ。
Hey, hey!
(イズミ)同期の うちはイタチ君でしょ。
Aren't you Itachi?
An Uchiha in my class?
一緒に遊ぼう。
Let's play together.
What do you want to do today?
今日は 何する？
Kick the can!
Let's play kick the can!
缶蹴りしようぜ 缶蹴り！
え～！
昨日も 缶蹴りだったじゃん。
Huh?
We played that yesterday!
おい！ テメエ シカトかよ。
Hey! Are you dissing us?
なんとか言え！
Say something!
(イタチ)
これから 手裏剣の練習だから。
I have shuriken training right now.
- Wow...
(みんな)ほぇ！
Well then…
んじゃあさ
俺たちも 手裏剣の練習しようぜ。
Let's practice shuriken too!
あっ ダメ！
フンッ！
No, don't!
アイツ…。
すかしやがって。 生意気な！
That kid!
Trying to act cool! What a stuck-up!
ちょっと！
アンタたち やめなさいよ！
Hey, you guys. Stop it!
うるせぇ！
これは 男と男の勝負なんだ。
Shut up!
This is between us guys!
《命は 生まれる》
《命は 死ぬ》
《命は 争う》
テメエ 逃げるな！
うわっ…。
(クシナ)うわ～！
(クシナ)女の子だっけ？
(ミコト)ウフフッ 男の子よ。
(クシナ)かわいい。
何て お名前でちゅか？
あぶぅ アハハ…。
(イタチ)ねえ 母さん。
四代目のとこにも
赤ちゃん 生まれるの？
(ミコト)そうよ。 どんな子かしらね。
母さん 今夜は 出かけるから
ご飯 食べてて。
わかった。
(ミコト)父さんも仕事だから→
サスケをお願いね。
うん。
(イタチ)今夜は 満月だよ サスケ。
あう～。
フフッ。
(イタチ)なんだ!?))